Jhal Hello Hello
everyone, today we are doing a
comparison between the pension plans of two very good life insurance companies. This is LIC's Jeevan
Shanti Pension Plan versus ICICI
Prudential Pension Plan. Both are market
leaders and very good companies
and both these products are very good. You will find a
comparison of these two products.
Pension planning is done very little in our country
and those who do it, it is
mostly seen that they
keep their money in deposits and earn income from that too, they
maintain their monthly expenses from that
and make deposits in subscriptions.
Accordingly, depending on fixed deposits can be
quite risky.
Such plans in the market are solving our tension
related problems to a great extent. Let's
start the comparison.
Thirty years maximum entries of both the products.
10 subscriptions in Shanti.
Different entries which we are
entering on the screen, you
can check by doing it, you can take a screenshot, if we talk about a quarter inch then
In both the products, the
subscriber appointed can start taking pension even after the appointed time.
The payment is single in both the products,
means whatever investment you have to make, you have to make it
in one shot. The deferment time in
ICICI Prudential is from one year to 10 years,
whereas in LIC it is available from one year to 12 years. If we
talk about minimum investment, then you should
invest at least Rs 12,500 in a year.
If someone is disabled, then he can invest a minimum of Rs 50,000. There is no
limit on maximum investment. In the mode of
appointment, the amount which is applicable in both the
products is less.
Both the companies provide this facility,
but you have to keep in mind
that if the policy goes into a quarter, then you will
get a little less. Select appointment.
In both the products, both single and joint
options are available. If we talk about benefits, then if the
policy holder dies tomorrow, then
subscribe and
subscribe for additional benefits, whichever of these happens, it is done.
It provides the option that
Situation but one can
take it in any, the sum can be in between 15 years,
women can go in free mode and this can
also go in free mode, example if
₹1000000 was done and someone dies, then
he can take it in 5 years,
10 years and 15 years which
can also be taken in the market, whereas in couples this
option is available, the company gives a
little extra interest benefit on doing it at extra premium,
if you do LIC policy
online then you get subscription, now let's
talk about which
companies have subscription, only two
variants are available, which is you Join with Written on
Purchase Price, that is,
you will keep getting pension and tomorrow
in the situation of your death, whatever is
your purchase price, that will be given to your nominee,
secondly your Join with Written to
Purchase Price subscription will keep on getting and the
entire subscription to the nominee is
optional, which is being put on the screen
and everyone  So explain this
point on Thursday, it is rich and may, that is,
whatever your pension is
decided according to your investment,
you will keep getting it regularly and whatever
amount you have invested in dowry, you will get it back
and you will be free for half an hour. The
second option is to subscribe to the YouTube channel of India.
You have
appointed and subscribed to the subscription of your investment
and the option that will continue to
run till you, if you are alive then you have got the
subscription, it will continue to run after that
and
whatever was your purchase price in the school situation,
it will be presented to your nominee. The
point is your immediate influence with return to
purchase from Feb 06, which you
decide, you will keep getting it
with the subscription and if the
date comes before the completion of the money, then the return to
purchase price is that option available in duty also in
which subscribe and
subscribe the
means that you select the partners for yourself, you
can take it single or
joint, Thursday is the second option.
You should subscribe to different E Laugh with
permanent disability and if the
policy holder has any permanent disability then
whatever you will be appointed, if we
talk about only two options available in this option then you can increase your pension by adding extra money in between top up if
you feel that you are short,
which
is available in both for your rich person
whereas this option is not available in LIC
subscribe extra benefits on Meghnad
for your existing customers for
example if you are a new customer then if
his pension is under it then existing
customers will have 129898 tension this
is optional not available in this surrender value
product before 3 years you will have more than 129898
while after 3 years your note will be deducted
which is both the products same you
can appoint Jeevan Shanti for 3 months for a
35 year old person who
wants to take tension for himself if that person invests 20 lakh
rupees in Jeevan  If you subscribe
on settings then the person who will become his bride will be
appointed ₹2000 subscribe our 16541
while the couple will be 1643
that you can dream that for interest
both the products are almost same from here there is not much
difference between the disgusting products please
like if you liked the video then
share it with people who keep
bringing such videos for themselves so please
subscribe and like our channel
thank you for watching